<JpmcExtensions>
  <EmailAlert>Y</EmailAlert>
  <Searchable>Y</Searchable>
  <SourceSystem>GPSAuthor</SourceSystem>
  <Permission>100</Permission>
  <BulletList>
    <component id="SUMMARY.ASCII.FORMATTEDBULLET" isBullet="Yes" order="1">Our iTraxx Main Technical Indicators (latest spread level 58.50bp S21, all spreads in this document and in our calculations are roll-adjusted): </component>
    <component id="SUMMARY.ASCII.FORMATTEDBULLET" isBullet="Yes" order="2">Momentum Indicator: Long risk trade 23 May 69.00bp</component>
    <component id="SUMMARY.ASCII.FORMATTEDBULLET" isBullet="Yes" order="3">Directional Movement Indicator: No trade at present </component>
    <component id="SUMMARY.ASCII.FORMATTEDBULLET" isBullet="Yes" order="4">Relative Strength Index: No trade at present </component>
    <component id="SUMMARY.ASCII.FORMATTEDBULLET" isBullet="Yes" order="5">House of Cards Indicator:  No trade at present </component>
    <component id="SUMMARY.ASCII.FORMATTEDBULLET" isBullet="Yes" order="6">Regime Switching Indicator:  Trending mode, Momentum long risk trade 1 July 59.75bp</component>
    <component id="SUMMARY.ASCII.FORMATTEDBULLET" isBullet="Yes" order="7">We track the performance of two portfolios – Portfolio A which is an equally weighted average of Momentum, DMI, RSI and House of Cards.  And separately, the Regime Switching Indicator on its own.</component>
    <component id="SUMMARY.ASCII.FORMATTEDBULLET" isBullet="Yes" order="8">Portfolio A P&amp;L over the past 12 months is 10.4bp, and 0.3bp YTD, Regime Switching model P&amp;L over the past 12 months is 30.9bp, and -2.8bp YTD</component>
    <component id="SUMMARY.ASCII.FORMATTEDBULLET" isBullet="Yes" order="9">If you would like to receive this publication on a more frequent basis (when a signal is produced), please email tina.t.zhang@jpmorgan.com to be added to our mailing list.</component>
    <component id="SUMMARY.ASCII.FORMATTEDBULLET" isBullet="Yes" order="10">While we try not to put too much emphasis on “technical analysis”, we have found that our indicators would have historically provided very good results for rules-based/algorithmic investors. The signals are also interesting to look at from the perspective of gauging how much impetus there is behind market moves – some indicators attempt to confirm whether a trend has been established, while the others attempt to signal turning points.</component>
    <component id="SUMMARY.ASCII.FORMATTEDBULLET" isBullet="Yes" order="11">Since our previous publication, our mean reversion indicators that put on short risk trades in early June have been forced to stop out of their trades.  </component>
    <component id="SUMMARY.ASCII.FORMATTEDBULLET" isBullet="Yes" order="12">As the pace of spread tightening has slowed, our Momentum model could close out of its long-held sell protection trade if spreads widen to the low-60s.</component>
  </BulletList>
  <ContentTypeList>
    <ContentType>PUBNOT</ContentType>
  </ContentTypeList>
  <PublicationID>9000237</PublicationID>
  <PrimaryAnalystList>
    <PrimaryAnalyst analystID="D113562">Tina T Zhang, CFA</PrimaryAnalyst>
  </PrimaryAnalystList>
  <SecondaryAnalystList>
    <SecondaryAnalyst analystID="U889246">Saul Doctor</SecondaryAnalyst>
  </SecondaryAnalystList>
  <PrimaryCompanyList />
  <SecondaryCompanyList />
  <ExpiryDate></ExpiryDate>
  <RICList />
  <RenderHtmlFlag>N</RenderHtmlFlag>
</JpmcExtensions>